András Gémes

shadowshell.io | github.com/gemesa | linkedin.com/gemesa | gemesa@protonmail.com

Summary

Compiler engineer specializing in reverse engineering with 7 years of cybersecurity experience. <u>Hands-on experience</u> in binary analysis, reverse engineering and malware analysis (e.g., ransomware and botnets). Certified in <u>Sec+</u>, <u>CASP+/SecX</u>, <u>CEH</u>, <u>PMAT</u>, <u>IMBT</u> and <u>others</u>. Looking to apply my expertise as a security engineer, reverse engineer or malware analyst.

Work experience

Compiler Engineer | Reverse Engineer @ *HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary*

Feb 2023 - Present

- Obfuscating the HighTec Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Representing HighTec as a member of the LLVM security group
- Implementing Rust and assembly tests for the HighTec Rust compiler

Application Security Engineer @ Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary

May 2018 - Jan 2023

- Implemented and evaluated static application security testing across C codebases
- Resolved vulnerabilities discovered through AFL++ fuzzing
- Developed and maintained an iOS app for real-time vehicle data visualization

Technical skills

Programming languages: C, C++, Rust, Objective-C, Swift, Python 3, Assembly (ARM64, x86-64), Bash

Reverse engineering (static): Ghidra, IDA, otool, llvm-objdump, ipsw, Binwalk, capa, YARA, DiE

Reverse engineering (dynamic): LLDB, GDB, Frida, QEMU, Qiling, strace, eBPF, VirtualBox, x64dbg

Vulnerability research: checksec, ROPgadget, AFL++, ASan, MSan, TSan, UBSan

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), macOS, Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Certifications

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH, TCM Security PMAT, Invoke RE IMBT and others.

Open source contributions

- ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches to Ghidra, focusing on the BSim, Debugger and FunctionID features
- <u>phantom-pass</u>: implementing custom LLVM-based obfuscator pass plugins
- o-mvll: improving the LLVM-based code obfuscator passes and diagnostics (focusing on iOS)
- <u>rust-arm64</u>: writing a Rust book (*Rust to assembly: ARM64 patterns*)
- <u>joern</u>: working on improved binary analysis capabilities through Ghidra integration
- shadow-shell: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

Education

MSc in Mechatronics Engineering

Feb 2016 - June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

BSc in Mechatronics Engineering

Sept 2012 - Jan 2016

University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary

Continuous education

Currently I am actively learning on TryHackMe and reading Advanced Apple Debugging & Reverse Engineering.